SUNGHEE YUN

sunghee.yun@gmail.com

Profile

I am Co-founder & CTO of AI Technology and Product Strategy @ Erudio Bio, Inc. with expertise in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Product and Technology Strategy. I have led AI and optimization projects in the fields such as semiconductor design / manufacturing / testing, strategic marketing and sales, e-commerce, industrial AI, and AI-enhanced biotech based on my fundamental understanding of the inner workings of and insight into AI with knowledge on convex optimization underpinning all AI algorithms.

My strength lies in applying core AI technologies such as large language model (LLM) and generative AI (genAI) for development and productionization of a number of software and services to many customers for B2B and B2C business. I am also consulted for state and government policy-making with topics such as potential changes of labor market driven by of AI technology, ethical, social and political issues on AI, and supply chain and manufacturing of AI semiconductor chips including CPU, GPU, and AI accelerators.

Before joining Erudio Bio, Inc., I co-founded Gauss Labs Inc., an industrial AI start-up company, as CTO & Head of Global R&D. I led many high-profile AI projects at Amazon increasing revenue by 200 million USD via Amazon Mobile Shopping App. Prior to Amazon, I worked for Samsung Electronics leading AI and optimization projects for semiconductor design, manufacturing, and testing.

WORK AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & CTO - AI Technology & Product Strategy, Erudio Bio, Inc.	Dec-2023 – Present
Adjunct Professor, Electronic Engineering Department, Sogang University	Mar-2020 - Present
Advisory Professor, Information and Communication Engineering, DGIST	Feb-2020-Present
Network Expert, Gerson Lehrman Gruop (GLG), New York City, U.S.A.	Feb-2022-Present
Co-founder & CTO - Senior Fellow, Gauss Labs Inc., Palo Alto, CA. U.S.A	May-2000 - Nov-2023
VP - Fellow, SK hynix	Sep-2020-Jun-2021
Senior Applied Scientist, Amazon.com, Inc., Vancouver, BC, Canada	Nov-2018 – Aug-2020
Principal Engineer, Software R&D Center, Samsung Electronics	Dec-2016 - Jun-2017
Principal Engineer, Strategic Sales & Marketing Team, Samsung Electronics	Dec-2015 - Dec-2016
Principal Engineer, Design Technology Team, Samsung Electronics	Mar-2012 - Nov-2015
Senior Engineer, CAE Team, Semiconductor R&D Center, Samsung Electronics	Dec-2004-Feb-2012
Research Assistant, EE Department, Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.	Mar-1999 - Nov-2004
Development Engineer, Voyan Technology, Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.	Sep-2000-Aug-2001
EDUCATION	
Ph.D., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd	Sep-2001 - Nov-2004
Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.	
M.S., Electrical Engineering - Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd	Sep-1998 - Jun-2000
Stanford University, CA, U.S.A.	
B.S., Electrical Engineering - Magna Cum Laude	Mar-1994 - Feb-1998
Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea	